JESWIN VARKEY GEORGE

Data Analyst, <u>Tableau Desktop Specialist</u>

Pune, Maharashtra, India | +91 8129737357 | <u>jeswinvgeorge22@gmail.com</u>
<u>LinkedIn profile</u> | <u>GitHub profile</u> | <u>Tableau public profile</u> | <u>My Website</u>

Objective

Data analyst with 2+ years of experience in the information technology and retail services industry. Excels at data wrangling, data mining and making dashboards using Python, R and Tableau. Seeking to apply my abilities to fill the Data Analyst role in your company.

Technologies

LANGUAGES: Python
DATABASES: PostgreSQL
TOOLS: Tableau, R, MS Excel
CLOUD: Microsoft Azure

Professional Experience

Infosys (Analytics unit), Pune, Senior Associate Analyst

Feb 2018-Present

➤ **Project:** Migrating a predictive model engine from Cloudera to MS Azure

Project duration: January 2020 – Present

Team strength: 3

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Creating and scheduling pipelines for the migration from Cloudera to Azure environment.
- Improving the engine to provide better prediction accuracy efficiently.
- Automating the different cases of data sanity check after migration.
- **Project:** Creating a baseline demand forecasting model for a retail giant.

Project duration: September 2019 – December 2019

Team strength: 3

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Assigned as data wrangler of the team.
- Scrapped websites to extract required data using Python (Beautiful soup).
- Cleaning and organising the unstructured data to tidy format using Python (Pandas).
- Applied EDA to get insights about the data using Python and Tableau.
- Created dashboards using Tableau for presentation to the client and higher management.
- Achieved accuracy of 90%.

➤ **Project:** PLM Data Migration for a retail client **Project duration:** July 2018 – August 2019 **Team strength:** 55 (Overall 5 teams)

Responsibilities and achievements:

- Teams: Data mining, Data matching, Data remediation, UI/BI and testing teams.
- Part of the Data matching engine creation team.
- Flagging the inconsistencies among the data from different ERPs using R, MS Excel and PostgreSQL.
- Unit testing and system testing of the developed matching engine.
- Ensure quick response to the issues raised by other teams or final application user.
- Analysing the impact of change request and logged defects at process level and project level.
- Created reports and dashboards using excel and R-shiny to present the results to the stakeholders.
- Mentoring new members joining the team and guiding them to get accustomed to the project environment.
- Achieved matching accuracy of 99.5%.

Udacity, Classroom Mentor

Dec 2017-Feb 2018

- Mentored students pursuing Udacity's Data Analyst Nanodegree program.
- Encouraged and guided 20 students assigned to me.

Side Projects

Identify Fraud from Enron Email

Link to project

• Applied machine learning to identify the fraud in the Enron scandal.

Wrangle Open Street Map Data

Link to project

• Wrangled Open street map data of New Delhi, India using Python.

Test a perceptual phenomenon – Stroop Effect

Link to project

• Applied inferential statistics on a test conducted on the Stroop effect.

EDA of red wine dataset

Link to project

• Applied exploratory data analysis techniques to get insights about the red wines dataset.

Scrapping website for hotels and their prices

Link to project

• Scrapped Goibibo website for hotels in Pune.

Tableau public profile

Link to project

• Collection of vizzes made by me in Tableau.

Education

Udacity, Data Analyst Nanodegree	June 2017 - Dec 2017
SRM University , MTech Communication Systems (CGPA – 7.24)	July 2015 - May 2017
University of Calicut, BTech ECE (CGPA – 7.04)	June 2010 - May 2014
CBSE , 12 th (Total percentage – 89.8%)	June 2008 - May 2010
ICSE, 10 th (Total percentage – 91.28%)	April 2007 - Mar 2008